# **Godspower Elema**

Lagos, 101245 / +2347011733379

elemagodspower@gmail.com | https://elemagodspower.com/

I am a front-end developer experienced in Javascript, ReactJS, SASS, CSS, Semantic-UI, Bootstrap, HTML, Styled Components amongst other tools. I am also experienced in consuming APIs. I have additional backend skills such as creation of APIs with JWT authentication system using NodeJS and Express. And database skills with MongoDB and Firebase. I am also experienced in using Git and Github for team collaboration and version control. I build clean, appealing and functional websites which comply with the latest web standards

## **EXPERIENCE**

### Front-end Developer Intern

Oct 2022 - Dec 2022

HNG, Lagos

- Worked with a team of developers, designers, marketers and product manager to ensure the timely delivery and launch of software products.
- Used git and github for collaboration with other developers.
- Build authentication systems and consumed APIs for the implementation of various features in the projects.
- Struck a balance between functional and aesthetic design.
- Ensured web design is responsive.
- Built reusable code for future use.
- Optimized web pages for maximum speed and scalability.
- Developed user-oriented visuals and features using front-end languages
- Ensured that all softwares built had strong SEO rankings.

#### **Front-end Developer**

Jan 2022 - Oct 2022

Freelance, Lagos

- Determined the structure and design of web pages.
- Struck a balance between functional and aesthetic design.
- Ensured web design is responsive.
- Optimized web pages for maximum speed and scalability.
- Developed user-oriented visuals and features using front-end languages
- Completed full redesigns of existing websites to improve navigation, enhance visuals and strengthen search engine SEO rankings.
- Consumed APIs to carry out operations in the projects.

## **EDUCATION**

#### **Web Development**

Jan 2021 - Dec 2021

ZTM Academy Bootcamp, Lagos

**Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.) - Metallurgical and Materials Engineering** Apr 2014 - Apr 2019 *Federal University of Technology, Owerri* 

## **SKILLS**

Javascript, ReactJS, HTML, CSS, SASS, Redux, Context API, NodeJS, ExpressJS, MongoDB, JWT Authentication, Git and Github, Communication skills